I only have three minutes
لديّ فقط ثلاث دقائق
so I'm going to have to talk fast, and it will
لذا يجب علي التحدث بسرعة,
use up your spare mental cycles, so multitasking may be hard.
استخدم دوراتك العقلية -- مهام منوعة قد تكون صعبة.
So, 27 years ago I got a traffic ticket
اذاً, منذ 27 سنة أخذت مخالفة سير
that got me thinking.
وهذا جعلني افكر.
I've had some time to think it over.
كان لديّ بعض الوقت لأفكر في الأمر.
And energy efficiency is more than just
الكفاءة في استخدام الطاقة هو أكثر من كونه
about the vehicle --
متعلقاً بالسيارة.
it's also about the road.
هو أيضاً يتعلق بالطريق.
Road design makes a difference, particularly intersections,
تصميم الطرق فيه اختلافات, ولاسيما التقاطعات,
of which there are two types: signalized
والتي يوجد منها نوعان: بإشارة
and unsignalized, which means stop signs.
وبدون إشارة, والتي تعني إشارة قف.
Fifty percent of crashes happen at intersections.
50% من الحوادث تحدث في التقاطعات.
Roundabouts are much better.
الدوارات أفضل بكثير.
A study of 24 intersections
هناك دراسة على 24 تقاطع
has found crashes drop 40 percent
وجدت أن الحوادث انخفضت 40 بالمئة
from when you convert a traffic light into a roundabout.
بعد تحويل إشارة المرور إلى دوّار.
Injury crashes have dropped 76 percent,
إصابات الحوادث انخفضت 76 بالمئة.
fatal crashes down 90 percent.
الحوادث القاتلة انخفضت 90 بالمئة.
But that's just safety.
وهذه مجرد السلامة.
What about time and gas?
ماذا عن الوقت والغاز؟
So, traffic keeps flowing, so that means less braking,
اذاً, السير يظل يتدفق, وهذا يعني استعمال أقل للكوابح,
which means less accelerating, less gas and less pollution,
والذي يعني أقل سرعة, أقل غاز و أقل تلوث,
less time wasted,
أقل تضييعاً للوقت,
and that partly accounts for Europe's better efficiency
وهذا جزئياً يحسب للكفاءة الأوربية التي هي أفضل
than we have in the United States.
مما عندنا في الولايات المتحدة.
So, unsignalized intersections,
إذاً, التقاطع بدون إشارة,
meaning stop signs, they save many lives,
تعني إشارات قف, إنها تنقذ الكثير من الأرواح,
but there's an excessive proliferation of them.
ولكن هناك إنتشار مفرط منها.
Small roundabouts are starting to appear.
دوّار صغير بدأ يظهر.
This is one in my neighborhood. And they are
هذا موجود في الحي الذي أعيش فيه. وهذه
much better -- better than traffic lights, better than four-way stop signs.
أفضل بكثير من الإشارات الضوئية, وأفضل من إشارات قف في الإتجاهات الأربع.
They're expensive to install,
إن تركيبها غالي الثمن ,
but they are more expensive not to. So, we should look at that.
ولكن عدم تركيبها أغلى.اذًا, يجب أن ننظر لهذا.
But they are not applicable in all situations.
و لكنها لا تنطبق على جميع الحالات.
So, take, for example, the three-way intersection.
اذاً, لنأخذ على سبيل المثال تقاطع بثلاث اتجاهات.
So, it's logical that you'd have one there,
اذاً, إنه من المنطقي أنك تحتاج واحدة هناك,
on the minor road entering the major.
على الطريق الثانوي دخولاً على الرئيسي.
But the other two are somewhat questionable.
لكن الإثنان الآخران مشكوك فيهما.
So, here's one. There's another one which I studied.
اذاً, هذا واحد. وهناك واحد آخر قمت بدراسته.
Cars rarely appear on that third road.
السيارات نادراً ما تظهر على ذلك الطريق الثالث.
And so, the question is, what does that cost us?
و السؤال هو, كم يكلفنا هذا؟
That intersection I looked at had about 3,000
التقاطع الذي رأيته يمر فيه حوالي 3,000
cars per day in each direction,
سيارة في اليوم في كل اتجاه,
and so that's two ounces of gas to accelerate out of.
فهذه أوقيتان من الغاز ل
That's five cents each, and times 3,000 cars per day,
هذه خمسة سنتات لكل منهما, و أوقات 3000 سيارة في اليوم,
that's $51,000 per year.
وهذا 51,000$ في السنة.
That's just the gasoline cost. There is also pollution,
وهذه فقط تكلفة الغاز. وهناك أيضاً التلوث,
wear on the car, and time.
صيانة السيارة, والوقت.
What's that time worth?
ماذا يساوي ذلك الوقت؟
Well, at 10 seconds per 3,000 cars,
حسناً, كل 10 ثواني ل 3,000 سيارة,
that's 8.3 hours per day. The average wage in the U.S.
هذا 8.3 ساعة في اليوم. و معدل الأجرة في الولايات المتحدة
is $20 an hour. That is 60,000 per year.
هي 20$ في الساعة. وهذا يعني 60,000 في السنة.
Add that together with the gas, and it's $112,000 per year,
اجمع هذا مع الغاز, وسيكون 112,000$ في السنة
just for that sign in each direction.
فقط لأجل تلك الإشارة في كل اتجاه.
Discount that back to the present, at five percent:
الخصم الذي يعود إلى الحاضر ، على خمسة في المئة :
over two million dollars
أكثر من مليوني دولار
for a stop sign, in each direction.
لإشارة قف, في كل إتجاه.
Now, if you look at what that adjacent property is worth,
الآن, اذا نظرتم إلى قيمة الممتلكات المجاورة,
you could actually buy the property,
فربما تشترونها,
cut down the shrubbery to improve the sight line,
تقصون الشجيرات لتحسين خط الأفق,
and then sell it off again.
ومن ثم بيعها من جديد.
And you'd still come out ahead.
وبالرغم من هذا يبقى الوضع أفضل.
So, it makes one wonder, "Why is it there?"
إذاً, إنها تعطي تساؤلاً, " لماذا هي هناك؟"
I mean, why is there that stop sign in each direction?
أعني, لماذا هناك إشارة قف في كل إتجاه؟
Because it is saving lives. So, is there a better way to accomplish that goal?
لأنها تنقذ الأرواح. إذاً, هل هناك طريقة أفضل لتحقيق هذا الهدف؟
The answer is to enable cars
الجواب هو تمكين السيارت
to come in from that side road safely.
لتأتي من ذلك الإتجاه بأمان.
Because there are a lot of people who might live up there
لأن هناك الكثير من الناس يعيشون هناك
and if they're waiting forever a long queue could form
وإذا انتظروا طويلاً سيتشكل طابور طويل
because the cars aren't slowing down on the main road.
لأن السيارات لا تخفف السرعة في الطريق الرئيسي.
Can that be accomplished with existing signs?
هل يمكن تحقيق ذلك مع الإشارات الموجودة؟
So, there is a long history of stop signs and yield signs.
إذاً, هناك تاريخ طويل لإشارات قف و الأولوية.
Stop signs were invented in 1915,
إشارة قف اخترعت عام 1915.
yield signs in 1950. But that's all we got.
و إشارة الأولوية في عام 1950. لكن هذا كل ما حصلنا عليه.
So, why not use a yield sign?
إذاً, لماذا لا تستخدم إشارة الأولوية؟
Well the meaning of yield is: You must yield the right-of-way.
معنى الأولوية هو : عليك أن تعطي حق الطريق.
That means that if there are five cars waiting, you have to wait
هذا يعني أنه إذا كان هناك خمس سيارات تنتظر, فعليك أن تنتظر
till they all go, then you go. It lacks the notion
حتى يذهبوا, ثم تذهب. إلا أنها تفتقر إلى مفهوم
of alternating, or taking turns,
التناوب, أو الدور.
and it's always on the minor road,
وهي دائماً على الطريق الثانوي
allowing the major one to have primacy.
وتسمح بالأولوية للطريق الرئيسي.
So, it's hard to create a new meaning for the existing sign.
لذا ، فإنه من الصعب إيجاد معنى جديد للعلامة الموجودة.
You couldn't suddenly tell everyone, "OK, remember
أنت لا تستطيع فجأة أن تقول للجميع ، "حسنا ، هل تذكرون
what you used to do at yield signs? Now do something different."
ما كنتم تفعلونه عند إشارات الأولوية؟ الآن افعلوا أشياء مختلفة."
That would not work.
هذا لن يعمل.
So, what the world needs now
اذاً, ما الذي يحتاجه العالم الآن
is a new type of sign.
هو إشارة جديدة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So, you'd have a little instruction below it,
لذا, سيكون هناك بعض التعليمات تحتها,
you know, for those who didn't see the public service announcements.
كما تعلمون ، لأولئك الذين لم يروا الإعلانات العامة.
And it merges the stop sign and yield signs.
وهي تدمج إشارتي قف و الأحقية.
It's kind of shaped like a T, as in taking turns.
إن شكلها مثل حرف T, كما في الدوران.
And uncertainty results in caution.
ونتائج غير مؤكدة في الحذر.
When people come to an unfamiliar situation they don't know how to deal with
عندما يمر الناس بموقف غير مألوف و لا يعرفون كيف يتصرفون معه
they slow down.
فهم يخففون السرعة.
So, now that you are all "Road Scholars" ...
إذاً, الآن أنتم جميعاً "علماء الطريق"...
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
don't wait for that sign to be adopted, these things don't change quickly.
لا تنتظروا هذه الإشارة حتى تعتمد, هذه الأشياء لا تتغير بسرعة.
But you all are members of communities,
ولكن جميعكم أعضاء في مجتمعات,
and you can exercise your community influence
ويمكنكم التأثير على مجتمعاتكم بالممارسة
to create more sensible traffic flows.
لخلق تدفقات معقولة لحركة المرور.
And you can have more impact on the environment
ويمكن أن يكون لكم أثر أكبر على المحيط
just getting your neighborhood to change these things
بأن تشجع الحي الذي تسكنه ليغير هذه الأشياء
than by changing your vehicle. Thank you very much.
من خلال تغيير سيارتك. شكراً جزيلاً.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)